[
    {
        "question": "Identify the deployment model among the following.",
        "answer": "Answer:  D) All of the above are deployment models.",
        "options": [
            "Private",
            "Public",
            "Hybrid",
            "All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Choose among the following which is related to services provided by the cloud.",
        "answer": "Answer:  B) Sourcing is related to services provided by the cloud.",
        "options": [
            "Reliability",
            "Souring",
            "Ownership",
            "AaaS"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Choose the correct IaaS provider among the following.",
        "answer": "Answer:  A) EC2 is the IaaS service provider.",
        "options": [
            "EC2",
            "EC1",
            "EC10",
            "Hybrid"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify among the components which are known as a hypervisor.",
        "answer": "Answer:  B) VMM is known as the hypervisor.",
        "options": [
            "VMC",
            "VMM",
            "VC",
            "All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Choose the correct relationship of cloud services to customers.",
        "answer": "Answer:  B) Cloud services are one-to-many relationships with their customers.",
        "options": [
            "One-One",
            "One-Many",
            "Many-one",
            "Many-Many"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following refers to network or internet?",
        "answer": "Answer:  C) Cloud computing refers to network or internet.",
        "options": [
            "Cloud",
            "CRM",
            "Cloud computing",
            "Computing"
        ]
    },
    null,
    {
        "question": "What does the term “elasticity” in cloud computing refer to?",
        "answer": "Answer:  D) Elasticity means the ability to scale down or scale-up.",
        "options": [
            "Ability to scale down",
            "Parallel",
            "Ability to scale up",
            "Both a and c are correct"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify among the following, which are examples of IaaS cloud computing",
        "answer": "Answer:  D) All of the above are examples of IaaS cloud computing.",
        "options": [
            "Linode",
            "Cisco meta cloud",
            "Digital ocean",
            "All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify among the following, which are examples of SaaS cloud computing.",
        "answer": "Answer:  D) All of the above are examples of SaaS cloud computing.",
        "options": [
            "Dropbox",
            "Salesforce",
            "Google workshop",
            "All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify among the following, which are examples of PaaS cloud computing",
        "answer": "Answer: D) All of the above are examples of PaaS cloud computing.",
        "options": [
            "Heroku",
            "Google App Engine",
            "AWS Elastic Beanstalk",
            "All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Choose among the following, which are the characteristics of IaaS.",
        "answer": "Answer:  D) All of the above are characteristics of IaaS.",
        "options": [
            "Highly scalable",
            "Flexible and dynamic platform",
            "Facilitates hardware access to many users",
            "All of the above"
        ]
    },
    null,
    {
        "question": "In cloud computing, the client is on which end.",
        "answer": "Answer:  B) Client is on the front end.",
        "options": [
            "Backend",
            "Frontend",
            "Depends",
            "Both a and b"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "In which year was Google Compute Engine released?",
        "answer": "Answer:  A) Google Compute Engine was released in 2012.",
        "options": [
            "2012",
            "2009",
            "2015",
            "2006"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the most important concern of cloud computing?",
        "answer": "Answer:  C) Security is the most important concern of cloud computing.",
        "options": [
            "Cost",
            "Space",
            "Security",
            "Platform"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Total types of cloud computing services are?",
        "answer": "Answer:  D) There are a total of 4 cloud computing services - public, private, hybrid, multi-clouds.",
        "options": [
            "1",
            "2",
            "3",
            "4"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "PaaS stands for?",
        "answer": "Answer:  A) PaaS stands for Platform as a service.",
        "options": [
            "Platform as a service",
            "Platform as a software",
            "Parallel as a service",
            "None"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "The term “hybrid cloud” refers to?",
        "answer": "Answer:  C) Hybrid cloud refers to the combination of private and public cloud.",
        "options": [
            "Private cloud",
            "Public cloud",
            "Combination of private and public cloud",
            "None"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the technique used for creating cloud computing.",
        "answer": "Answer:  C) Virtualization is the technique used for creating cloud computing.",
        "options": [
            "Insubordination",
            "Cannibalization",
            "Virtualization",
            "Transubstantiation"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Total steps of deployment stage in cloud computing are?",
        "answer": "Answer:  B) The total deployment stage in cloud computing is 4.",
        "options": [
            "3",
            "4",
            "5",
            "6"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify among the following, which provides a runtime environment.",
        "answer": "Answer:  C) PaaS provides a runtime environment for applications.",
        "options": [
            "IaaS",
            "SaaS",
            "PaaS",
            "XaaS"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "SAN stands for ______",
        "answer": "Answer:  A) SAN stands for Storage area network.",
        "options": [
            "Storage area network",
            "Security area network",
            "Switch application network",
            "None"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the most basic level of storage.",
        "answer": "Answer:  C) DAS is the most basic level of storage.",
        "options": [
            "NAS",
            "SAN",
            "DAS",
            "ISCSI"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the storage technologies among the following which have the best performance.",
        "answer": "Answer:  B) SAN has the best performance among all others.",
        "options": [
            "NAS",
            "SAN",
            "DAS",
            "None"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Among the following layers, which are not related to SAN architecture.",
        "answer": "Answer:  D) Object layer is not related to SAN architecture.",
        "options": [
            "Storage layer",
            "Host layer",
            "Fabric layer",
            "Object layer"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Among the following, which provides the GUI for interaction with the cloud.",
        "answer": "Answer:  C) Client infrastructure provides the GUI for interaction with the cloud.",
        "options": [
            "Server",
            "Client",
            "Client infrastructure",
            "Application"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Choose among the following options, on which utility computing is based.",
        "answer": "Answer:  D) Utility computing is based on SOA.",
        "options": [
            "Virtual isolation model",
            "Grid Computing model",
            "Pay-per use model",
            "SOA"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "On what is cloud computing-based.",
        "answer": "Answer:  C) Cloud computing is based on virtualization.",
        "options": [
            "Modulation",
            "Hybridization",
            "Virtualization",
            "Multiplexing"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is a cloud?",
        "answer": "Answer:  A) Hadoop can be considered as a cloud.",
        "options": [
            "Hadoop",
            "Web applications",
            "Intranet",
            "None"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "SaaS stands for?",
        "answer": "Answer: B) SaaS stands for Software as a service.",
        "options": [
            "Scalability as a service",
            "Software as a service",
            "Service as a software",
            "None"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Total types of hypervisors are?",
        "answer": "Answer: A) There are two types of hypervisors.",
        "options": [
            "2",
            "3",
            "4",
            "5"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Total types of PaaS are?",
        "answer": "Answer:  C) There are four types of hypervisors.",
        "options": [
            "2",
            "3",
            "4",
            "5a"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "QPS stands for?",
        "answer": "Answer:  D) QPS stands for Query per second.",
        "options": [
            "Query period sites",
            "Quantum per second",
            "Quality Per Service",
            "Query per second"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Choose the most important use of cloud computing.",
        "answer": "Answer:  B) Data storage is the most important use of cloud computing.",
        "options": [
            "Data privacy",
            "Data storage",
            "Cost-effective",
            "Security"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is a cloud platform by amazon?",
        "answer": "Answer:  C) Amazon provided AWS cloud service.",
        "options": [
            "Cloudera",
            "Azure",
            "AWS",
            "All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify among the following, which monitors the performance of major cloud-based services in real-time.",
        "answer": "Answer:  B) CloudSensor monitors the performance of major cloud-based services in real-time.",
        "options": [
            "CloudMetrices",
            "CloudSensor",
            "CloudWatch",
            "None"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "GAE stands for?",
        "answer": "Answer:  A) GAE stands for Google apps engine.",
        "options": [
            "Google apps engine",
            "Google applied to engineer",
            "Google architecture engineering",
            "None"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the most restrictive and most refined cloud service model.",
        "answer": "Answer:  D) PaaS is the most restrictive and most refined cloud service model.",
        "options": [
            "IaaS",
            "XaaS",
            "SaaS",
            "PaaS"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following terms refers to the management and location of cloud infrastructure.",
        "answer": "Answer:  B) Deployment refers to the management and location of cloud infrastructure.",
        "options": [
            "Application",
            "Deployment",
            "Service",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the types of dimensions in Cloud Cube?",
        "answer": "Answer:  C) There are 4 types of dimensions in Cloud Cube.",
        "options": [
            "2",
            "3",
            "4",
            "5"
        ]
    },
    null,
    {
        "question": "IaaS stands for?",
        "answer": "Answer:  B) IaaS stands for Infrastructure as a service",
        "options": [
            "Information as a service",
            "Infrastructure as a service",
            "Infrastructure as a software",
            "None"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the highest degree of integration of cloud computing.",
        "answer": "Answer: A) SaaS is the highest degree of integration of cloud computing.",
        "options": [
            "SaaS",
            "PaaS",
            "IaaS",
            "CaaS"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Choose among the following which allows the different OS to run in their memory space.",
        "answer": "Answer:  C) VMM allows the different OS to run in their memory space.",
        "options": [
            "VMS",
            "VMS",
            "VMM",
            "All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the VM monitor and CPU emulator among the following.",
        "answer": "Answer:  B) QEMU is the VM monitor and CPU emulator.",
        "options": [
            "Parallels",
            "QEMU",
            "VMS",
            "None"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the Type 1 hypervisor among the following.",
        "answer": "Answer:  D) KVM is the Type 1 hypervisor.",
        "options": [
            "KVM",
            "Virtual Server 2005 R2",
            "Wind River Simics",
            "KVM"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "IT Architecture Development comes under which of the following phases.",
        "answer": "Answer:  A) IT Architecture Development under planning phase.",
        "options": [
            "Planning phase",
            "Development phase",
            "Strategy phase",
            "Testing phase"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Total types of cloud architecture are?",
        "answer": "Answer:  B) There is a total of two types of cloud architecture - frontend and backend.",
        "options": [
            "1",
            "2",
            "3",
            "4"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "By whom is the backend used primarily?",
        "answer": "Answer:  B) Backend is used primarily by Service providers.",
        "options": [
            "User",
            "Service provider",
            "Client",
            "Stockholders"
        ]
    }
]